rina.org.uk 2019-08-31

# Privacy Statement

* * *

The Royal Institution of Naval Architects (RINA) is committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful and safe online experience. This Statement of Privacy applies to the RINA website and governs data collection and usage. By using the RINA website, you consent to the data practices described in this statement.

## Collection of your Personal Information

RINA collects personally identifiable information, such as your email address, name, home or work address or telephone number. RINA also collects anonymous demographic information, which is not unique to you, such as your PO/ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favourites.

There is also information about your computer hardware and software that is automatically collected by RINA. This information can include: your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. This information is used by RINA for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the RINA website.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personally identifiable information or personally sensitive data through RINA public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. Note: RINA does not read any of your private online communications.

RINA encourages you to review the privacy statements of websites you choose to link to from RINA so that you can understand how those websites collect, use and share your information. RINA is not responsible for the privacy statements or other content on websites outside of the RINA controlled websites.

## Use of your Personal Information

RINA collects and uses your personal information to operate the RINA website and deliver the services you have requested. RINA also uses your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from RINA and other authorised organisations. RINA may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

RINA does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. RINA may, from time to time, contact you on behalf of external business partners about a particular offering that may be of interest to you. In those cases, your unique personally identifiable information (email, name, address, telephone number) is not transferred to the third party. In addition, RINA may share data with trusted partners to help us perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to RINA, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

RINA does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

RINA keeps track of the websites and pages our customers visit within RINA, in order to determine what RINA services are the most popular. This data is used to deliver customised content and advertising within RINA to customers whose behaviour indicates that they are interested in a particular subject area.

RINA websites will disclose your personal information, without notice, only if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on RINA or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of RINA; and, (c) act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of RINA, or the public.

## Use of Cookies

The RINA website use "cookies" to help you personalise your online experience. A cookie is a text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server. Cookies cannot be used to run programmes or deliver viruses to your computer. Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.

The RINA website uses “session” cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time. The purpose of a session cookie is to tell the Web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalise RINA pages, or register with RINA site or services, the cookie helps RINA to recall your specific information on subsequent visits. This simplifies the process of recording your personal information, such as billing addresses, shipping addresses, and so on. When you return to the same RINA website, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the RINA features that you customised.  The cookie is named c2rina_rin2344ska3 and will last for 3 months.

As we improve our website over time, similar and more advanced features may be added that also require a cookie to operate.

You may restrict or block the cookies which are set by the RINA website, or any other website, through your browser settings. To find out more about cookies and how to manage them, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the RINA services or websites you visit.

The RINA website also uses cookies to allow Google Analytics to function correctly. Google Analytics is a free web analytics tools that helps us understand how visitors engage with the RINA website. These cookies have names that begin with __utm such as __utma and __utmz.

Google Analytics collects information anonymously; it reports website trends without identifying individual visitors. The cookies store information such as the number of visits to the website and what site referred the visitor to the web page. We use the information to view reports about how visitors interact with the website and to help us improve the website. A different set of cookies is used for each website, and visitors are not tracked across multiple sites.  To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites visit <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>

The RINA website uses Adobe Flash Player to provide video content. Local Shared Objects (commonly known as “Flash Cookies”) may be used to improve user experience, for example to save your playback preferences.  Information on how to disable and delete Flash Cookies is provided on the Adobe website at [www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/security](http://www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/security).  Your experience of the RINA website may be affected if you restrict the use of Flash Cookies.

## Security of your Personal Information

RINA secures your personal information from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. RINA secures the personally identifiable information you provide on computer servers in a controlled, secure environment, protected from unauthorised access, use or disclosure. When personal information (such as a credit card number) is transmitted to other websites, it is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

## Changes to this Statement

RINA will occasionally update this Statement of Privacy to reflect company and customer feedback. RINA encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how RINA is protecting your information.

## Contact Information

RINA welcomes your comments regarding this Statement of Privacy. If you believe that RINA has not adhered to this Statement, please contact the Chief Executive of RINA at [hq@rina.org.uk](mailto:hq@rina.org.uk). We will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and remedy the problem.
